Part 2. Listening comprehension.
Section A. Directions.
this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then, mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Conversation 1.
Mr. Ishiguro, have you ever found one of your books at a second -hand bookstore?
Yes, that kind of thing is difficult.
If they've got my book there, I think, well,
is an insult.
Somebody didn't want to keep my book.
But if it's not there, I feel it's an insult too.
I think, why aren't people exchanging my book?
Why isn't it in this store?
Does being a writer require a thick skin?
Yes. For example, my wife can be very harsh.
I began working on my latest book, The Buried Giant, in 2004.
But I stopped after I showed my wife a little section.
She thought it was rubbish.
Even after you won a Booker Prize?
She's not intimidated at all.
And she criticizes me in exactly the same way she did when I was first unpublished
and I was starting.
But you would never compromise on your vision.
No, I wouldn't ever compromise on the essential, the ideas, or the themes.
This isn't really what my wife is trying to criticize me about.
It's always about execution.
So why did you put your book, The Buried Giant, aside for so long?
Apparently you started working on it over ten years ago.
I've often stopped writing a and left it for a few years.
And by the time I come back to it, it may have changed.
my imagination has moved on.
And I can think of different contexts or a different way to do it.
What does it feel like when you finally finish a It's funny you ask that because I
never have this moment when I feel,
I've finished. I watch footballers at the end of the match, you know, the whistle
goes and they've won or Until then, they've been giving everything they have and at
that moment they know it's over.
It's funny for an author.
There's never a finishing whistle.
Questions 1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 1. How would the man feel if he found his book in a secondhand bookstore?
Question 2. What does the man's wife think of his books?
Question 3. What does the man do when he engages in writing?
Question 4. What does the man want to say by mentioning the football match?
Conversation 2. to a study of race and equity in education, black athletes are
dropping out of college across the country at alarming rates.
With us to talk about the findings in the study is Washington Post columnist Kevin
Blackstone. Good morning.
Good morning. How are you?
Fine, thank you.
What is new that you found in this study?
Well, this is Sean Harper's study and he points out that on major college campuses
across the country, black males make up less than 3 of undergraduate enrollments.
Yet, when you look at their numbers or percentages on the revenue -generating sports
teams of football and basketball, they make up well into 50 to 60 of those teams.
So the idea is that they are really there to be part of the revenue -generating
working class of athletes on campus and not necessarily there to be part of the
educating class as most students in other groups are.
Compared with other groups, I think the numbers in this group at those 65 schools
are something like just barely, more than half of the black male athletes graduate
at all. Exactly.
And what's really bad about this is these athletes are supposedly promised at least
one thing as reward for all their blood and sweat.
And that is a college degree, which can be a transformative tool in our society when
you talk about upward mobility.
And that's really the troubling part about this.
Well, this has been talked about so much, really, in recent years.
Why hasn't it changed?
Well, I think one of the reasons it hasn't changed is because there's really no
economic pressure to change this.
All of the incentive is really on winning and not losing on the field or on the
court. Coaches do not necessarily have the incentive to graduate players.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. What are the speakers talking about?
Question 6. What is the new finding about black male athletes in this study?
Question 7. What is the graduation rate of black male athletes?
Question 8. What accounts for black athletes' failure to obtain a college degree
according to the man?
Section B. Directions.
this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Passage 1.
America's holiday shopping season starts on Black Friday, the day after
Thanksgiving. It is the busiest shopping day of the year.
Retailers make the most money this time of year, about 20 to 30 percent of annual
revenue. About 136 million people will shop during the Thanksgiving holiday weekend.
More and more will shop online.
In an era of instant information, shoppers can use their mobile phones to find
deals. About 183.8 million people will shop on Cyber Monday, the first Monday after
Thanksgiving. More than half of all holiday purchases will be made online.
One in five Americans will use a tablet or smartphone.
Online spending on Black Friday will rise 15 percent to hit $2.7 billion this year.
Cyber Monday spending will increase 12 percent to $3 billion.
For many, shopping online was a more comfortable alternative than crowded malls.
The shift to online shopping has had a big impact on traditional shopping malls.
Since 2010, more than 24 shopping malls have closed and an additional 60 are
struggling. However, Fortune says the weakest of the malls have closed.
The sector is thriving again.
The International Council of Shopping Centers said 94.2 percent of malls were full
or occupied with shops by the end of 2014.
That is the highest level in 27 years.
Economist Gus Foucher said lower unemployment and rising wages could give Americans
more money to spend.
The average American consumer will spend about $805 on gifts.
That's about $630.5 billion between November and December, an increase of 3.7
percent from last year.
Question 10. How many people will shop on Cyber Monday?
Question 11. What does Fortune say about traditional shopping malls?
Question 12. What is said to account for the increased number of shoppers?
Passage 2. For years, many of us have relied on antibiotic use to treat various
infections. And the reality is that antibiotics have been responsible for saving
millions of lives since penicillin, one of the earliest antibiotics, was first used
on a clinical basis 70 years ago.
However, today is a new era in which taking antibiotics can cause some very
dangerous and potentially life -threatening situations.
In fact, you may have heard about the new superbugs,
which are antibiotic -resistant bacteria that have developed as a result of
overprescribed antibiotics.
In the past, health experts warned us that the day would come in which it would
become very difficult to provide medical care for even common problems, such as lung
infection or severe sore throat.
And apparently that day has come because seemingly routine operations, such as knee
replacements, are now much more hazardous due to the looming threat of these
infections. The problem has grown into such epidemic proportions that this severe
strain of resistant bacteria is being blamed for nearly 700,000 deaths each year
throughout the world.
And unfortunately, health experts worry that the number will rise to 10 million or
more on a yearly basis by 2050.
With such a large life -threatening epidemic, it is sad to say that only 1.2
of budgetary money for the National Institutes of Health is currently being spent on
research to tackle this problem.
This is a far cry from the funds necessary for a problem of such magnitude.
Question 14. What is the result of the overuse of antibiotics?
Question 15. What is most urgently needed for tackling the large life -threatening
epidemic, according to the speaker?
Section C. Directions.
In this section, you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks followed by
three or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with this single line through
the center. I think about some of the students who took advantage of their
opportunities in a university.
One of the stories I always like to tell is of a freshman seminar that I had a
chance to teach at Harvard when I was president of the university.
I taught a seminar on globalization and I assigned a reading that I had written
about global capital flows.
And, as I did each week,
I asked one of the students to introduce the readings.
And this young man, in October of his freshman year, said something like the
following. The reading by President Summers on the flow of capital across countries,
it was kind of interesting, but the data did not come close to supporting the
conclusions. And I thought to myself, what a fantastic thing this was.
How could somebody who had been there for five weeks tell the person who had the
title president that he didn't really know what he was talking about?
And it was a special moment.
Now, I don't want to be misunderstood.
I explained to my student that I actually thought he was rather more confused than I
was. And I argued back.
But what was really important about that was the universities stand out as places
that really are about the authority of ideas.
You see it in faculty members who are pleased when their students make a discovery
that undermines a cherished theory that they had put forward.
I think of another student I had who came to me one morning, one evening, actually
walked into my office and said that I had written a pretty good paper, but that it
had five important mistakes and that he wanted a job.
You could debate whether they actually were mistakes, but you couldn't debate that
young man's hunger to learn.
You could not debate that that young man was someone who wanted to make a difference
in economics. And he is today a professor of economics, and his works are more cited
as an economist than any other economist in the world.
Question 17. What do we learn from the speaker's stories about universities?
Question 18. What does the speaker see in the young man who challenged his paper?
Question What does the in the young man who challenged his paper?
Question 20. What does the see in the young man who challenged his paper?
Question 21. What does the speaker
Question 22. What does the speaker see in
Question 23. What does the speaker young man who
Question 24. What does the
Question 25. What does the see in the young man paper?
Question 20. What do we learn about the two lists in the test?
Question 21. What does the speaker suggest about preparing for and taking an exam?
Question 22. What tip does the speaker give on learning?
Question 23. What tips does the speaker give on learning?
Question 24. What tips does the
Question 25. tips does the speaker give on learning?
Question 25. What tips does the
Question 25. What tips does the speaker give on learning?
Question 25. What tips does the learning?
Question 25. tips the speaker give
Question 25. What tips the speaker give learning?
Question 25. What tips does the speaker give on learning?
This is the end of listening comprehension.